American Congregational Association records, 1846-2022.
Congregational Library & Archives
- Congregational Library & Archives records, 1853 2022; 1853-2022; 155 Folders; 9 Volumes
  - Collections, 1853 2004; 1853-2004; 24 Folders; 1 Volume
    - Periodical project, 1997 2000; 1997-2000 (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - Microfilm projects, 1997 2004; 1997-2004 (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - Microfilm projects, 1998 2004; 1998-2004 (Box 14, Folder 32)
    - Book lists, undated (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Researcher and reference correspondence, 1897 2004; 1897-2004; 20 Folders
    Restrictions on Access
    This subseries is restricted and not available to library users. This restriction is not expected to expire.
    This subseries contains records related to reference requests and correspondence with researchers.
    - Reference correspondence, 1897 1964; 1897-1964 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Harold Worthley reference correspondence, 1977 1979; 1977-1979 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Researcher correspondence, 1979 1987; 1979-1987 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Harold Worthley reference correspondence, 1980 1981; 1980-1981 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Harold Worthley reference correspondence, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Harold Worthley reference correspondence, 1982 1983; 1982-1983 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Harold Worthley reference correspondence, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Harold Worthley reference correspondence, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Harold Worthley reference correspondence, 1986 1988; 1986-1988 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Researcher correspondence, 1987 1989; 1987-1989 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Harold Worthley reference correspondence, 1988 1989; 1988-1989 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Harold Worthley reference correspondence, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Reference correspondence, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Reference correspondence, 1997 2003; 1997-2003 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Harold Worthley reference correspondence, 1998 2003; 1998-2003 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Researcher correspondence, 1998 1999; 1998-1999 (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Researcher correspondence, 1999 2004; 1999-2004 (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Researcher correspondence, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - Researcher correspondence, 2001 2004; 2001-2004 (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - Researcher correspondence, 2002 2003; 2002-2003 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Congregational Christian Historical Society records, 1951 2008; 1951-2008; 6 Folders
    This subseries contains records related to the Congregational Christian Historical Society (CCHS). The Society was founded by Frederick L. Fagley and following his death the society moved to the Congregational House. Over time, the functions of the CCHS were absorbed into the Congregational Library & Archives. By the 21st century, the executive director of the CCHS was also the executive director of the Library and by 2008 the CCHS, and its mission, was formally merged into the Library. This subseries contains some few records related to the history of the CCHS, as well as records related to the merger of the CCHS into the Congregational Library & Archives.
    Related Materials
    The Congregational Library & Archives maintains the archive of the Congregational Christian Historical Society. The collection, titled "Congregational Christian Historical Society records, 1899-2010" (RG1187) is available to researchers interested in the history of the organization upon request. More information about the collection, as well as a link to the collection's finding aid, may be found in the collection's catalog record.
    - Establishment rescords, 1951 (Box 15, Folder 43)
    - Congregational Historical Society clippings, 1952 1959; 1952-1959 (Box 32, Folder 17)
    - Employee share issues, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 44)
    - Finances and membership, 1990 2006; 1990-2006 (Box 15, Folder 45)
    - Collaboration, 2003 2004; 2003-2004 (Box 15, Folder 46)
    - Merger, 2008 (Box 15, Folder 47)
  - Facilities, 1963 2020; 1963-2020; 24 Folders
    This subseries contains records directly related to the physical facilities of the Congregational Library & Archive. Most of this series contains records related to construction and renovation projects solely devoted to the expansion, maintenance, or improvement of the Library's facilities. Of particular note are records related to the construction of the Rare Book Room, the construction of the Library's award-winning HVAC system, and the renovation and expansion of the Library's offices in the wake of the American Congregational Association's sale of the Congregational House.
    - Rare Book Room construction records, 1963 1968; 1963-1968 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Rare Book Room construction specifications, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Climate control survey, 1990 1997; 1990-1997 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Rare Book Room maintenance, 1992 1999; 1992-1999 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Preservation survey, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Environmental conditions survery, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Library environmental assessment, 1993 (Box 32, Folder 19)
    - Library security, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Reading room preservation restriction, 1998 (Box 32, Folder 20)
    - Environmental report, 1999 2000; 1999-2000 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - HVAC project estimate, 1999 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - HVAC system sketches, 2001 2002; 2001-2002 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - HVAC records, 2001 2003; 2001-2003 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - HVAC contract, 2003 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - LC Anderson maintenance program, 2003 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - HVAC as built drawings, 2003 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Sprinkler system evaluation, 2010 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Renovation project owner's representative proposal, 2018 (Box 32, Folder 26)
    - Renovation project proposal, 2018 (Box 32, Folder 27)
    - Renovation project cost estimates, 2018 (Box 32, Folder 28)
    - Renovation project programming, planning, design proposal, 2018 (Box 32, Folder 29)
    - Renovation project construction documents, 2019 (Box 32, Folder 30)
    - Renovation project meeting minutes, 2019 2020; 2019-2020 (Box 32, Folder 31)
    - Renovation project field report, 2020 (Box 32, Folder 32)
- Photographic and audio-visual materials, 1953 2013; 1953-2013, undated; 28 Folders; 3 Boxes
  This series contains photographic and audio-visual materials about the Congregational Library & Archives and the American Congregational Association. The photographs include images of the Congregational House, both exterior and interior, images of Congregationalists, images of building and library staff, as well as images of events. The audio-visual materials include interviews, such as an interview production with Hal Worthley, images on CDs, and materials related to programs and events related to the library and association.
  - 100th anniversary photographs, 1953 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Photographs of staff, 1963 2005; 1963-2005 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Dedication of the Rare Book Room, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Board photographs, 1990 1998; circa 1990-1998 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Collections photographs, 2001, undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Architectural drawings, 2002 2006; 2002-2006 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - 150th anniversary photographs, 2003 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Carol Doherty retirement party photograph, 2008 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Historic Boston Incorporated photograph, 2009 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Mather redux photograph, 2013 (Box 32, Folder 23)
  - Glass plates, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Congregational House photographs, undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Photographs of people, undated (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Slides and PR materials, undated (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Photographic materials, A, undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Photographic materials, B, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Photographic materials, C-Dana, undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Photographic materials, D, undated (Box 18, Folder 4-5)
  - Photographic materials, E-Fe, undated (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Photographic materials, Fi-G, undated (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Photographic materials, H, undated (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Photographic materials, J-N, undated (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Photographic materials, M, undated (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Photographic materials, P-Se, undated (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Photographic materials, Sm-St, undated (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Photographic materials, V-W, undated (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Congregational House exterior, undated (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous photographic materials, undated (Box 19)
  - Miscellaneous audio-visual materials, undated (Box 20)
  - Objects, undated (Box 21)
  - Building exterior, undated (Folder 9)